嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
琼还好吗   跟她分手了
So how was Joan? Broke up with her.
哦  为什么
Oh, why?
别说  是鼻孔太大的问题吗
Don't tell me. Because of the big nostril thing?
真的很大
They were huge.
她打喷嚏的时候  会有蝙蝠飞出来
When she sneezed, bats flew out of them.
得了吧  没那么大啦
Come on, they were not that huge.
我告诉你  她一躺下我就能看穿她的大脑
I'm telling you, she leaned back, I could see her brain.
你还要拒绝多少好女人
How many women will you reject...
只为了外表或不重要的小事…
...over the most superficial, insignificant things?
等等  这次我要站在钱德这一边
Hold it. Hold it. I gotta side with Chandler on this one.
我刚搬到这里的时候  有跟一个女孩约会
When I first moved to the city, I went out with this girl.
真的很辣  很会接吻
Really hot. Great kisser...
可是她的喉结超大的
...but she had the biggest Adam's apple.
快把我逼疯了
Drove me nuts.
你来还是我来   我来好了
You or me?  I got it.
乔伊  女人是没有喉结的
Joey, women don't have Adam's apples.
你们又在恶整我了  对吧
Heh, heh. You guys are messing with me, right?
对  正是
Yeah. We are.
这次很厉害  刚才我还在想〝哦〞
That's a good one. For a second there, I was like, whoa!
《老友记》  第二季  第3集  黑考斯死掉了
Friends S02E03: The One Where Mr. Heckles Dies
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
你举出一个有实际的理由才分手的女人
So you name one woman that you broke up with for an actual real reason.
玛琳·摩丝拉
Maureen Rasillo.
她不讨厌雅尼  不能算是实际的理由
Because she doesn't hate Yanni is not a real reason.
哈罗  黑考斯先生
Hello, Mr. Heckles.
你们又来了
You're doing it again.
我们没做什么啊
We're not doing anything.
你们在跺脚  吵到我的鸟了
You're stomping. It's disturbing my birds.
你又没有养鸟
You don't have birds.
我原来可养鸟的
I could have birds.
我们会尽量小声啦   谢谢
Okay, we'll try to keep it down. Thank you.
（制片：塔德·史帝文斯）
我要回去享受我的晚宴了
I'm going to rejoin my dinner party.
好吧  拜拜
All right, bye-bye.
（制片：贝西·伯恩斯）
好  珍妮丝 就说珍妮丝好了 那可不叫挑剔了
Okay, Janice. You gotta give me Janice. That wasn't about being picky.
（编剧：麦克·寇帝斯 葛雷哥利·麦林斯）
珍妮丝为例还可以
We'll give you Janice.
虽然说我会想念珍妮丝
I miss Janice, though.
哈罗  钱德宾
Hello, Chandler Bing!
哦  我的天  哦  钱德
Oh, my God! Oh, Chandler!
（导演：凯文·布莱特）
快  快
Now! Now!
就是这样
That's it.
对  快点
There! Faster!
放下你的扫把  我们又没有制造噪音
Ugh. Stop with the broom! We're not making noise!
我们赢了
We won.
我们成功了
We won! Whoo!  Whoo!
黑考斯先生
Mr. Heckles.
怎么发生的  当时他一定是在扫地
How did this happen?  He was sweeping.
他们发现他还拿着扫把
They found a broom in his hand.
太可怕了  我知道
Oh.Oh, dear God. That's terrible. I know.
昨天我也有扫地
I was sweeping yesterday.
也有可能是我
It could've been me. Yeah.
扫地  真是没想到
Sure. Sweeping. You never know.
真是天晓得
Never know.
好  很微弱  不过我还是可以感觉到他还在这栋建筑物里
Okay, it's very faint, but I can still sense him in the building.
快走到光里面  黑考斯先生
Go into the light, Mr. Heckles!
好了  菲比
Okay, Phoebe.
很抱歉  不过有时候他们是需要协助的
I'm sorry, but sometimes they need help.
对  又来了
Yeah. Here we go.
没关系  你们尽管嘲笑我
That's fine, go ahead and scoff.
有很多东西我并不相信...
There are a lot of things I don't believe in...
也不代表那些东西就不存在
...but that doesn't mean they're not true.
比如
Such as?
比如玉米田的圆圈圈  或百慕达三角  或进化论
Like crop circles or the Bermuda Triangle or evolution.
哇  哇  哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哈  你不相信进化论
What, you don't believe in evolution?
不是很信
No. Not really.
你不相信进化论
You don't believe in evolution?
我不知道  只是  就是…
I don't know. It's just, you know...
猴子啦  达尔文啦  故事是不赖  我只是觉得太简单了
Monkeys, Darwin, it's a nice story. I just think it's a little too easy.
太简单  太…
"Too easy"? Too...
本星球上所有生物的进化过程…
The process of every living thing on this planet evolving...
从单细胞生物开始千百万年的进化  你说〝太简单〞了
...over millions of years from single-celled organisms is "too easy"?
对  我就是不相信这套理论
Yeah, I just don't buy it.
抱歉  进化论  不在于你信或不信  菲比
Excuse me. Evolution is not for you to buy, Phoebe.
进化论是科学的事实 就像我们所呼吸的空气
Evolution is scientific fact, like the air we breathe...
就像地心引力
...like gravity.
别惹我开始谈地心引力
Okay, don't get me started on gravity.
你…
You, uh...
你不相信地心引力
You don't believe in gravity?
不在于我信或不信啦
Well, it's not so much that, you know, I don't believe in it.
只是我近来觉得…
Lately I get the feeling that...
我没感受到一股拉力  倒是觉得很被压抑
...I'm not so much being pulled down as I am being pushed.
被压抑
Pushed.
牛顿来了  而且他很火大
Uh-oh. It's Isaac Newton and he's pissed.
她在 还有另外那个 就在那边
There she is. And over there, that's the other one.
他是黑考斯的律师巴迪  他要跟你们谈谈
This is Mr. Buddy Boyle, Heckles' attorney. He'd like to talk to you.
我们能帮什么忙
What can we do for you?
好了  孩子们  情况是这样
All right, kids, here's the deal.
根据我客户的遗嘱
According my client's will...
他想把他所有的资产留给…
...he wants to leave all his earthly possessions...
〝住在我公寓上方那些吵死人的女孩子们〞
...to "the noisy girls in the apartment above mine."
他的家人呢
What about his family?
他没有家人
He didn't have any. Whoa.
好  那我们就来谈钱的问题
Okay, so let's talk money.
可以  钱是没有
All right, there was none.
现在  谈签字的事了
Now, let's talk signing.
你是第一号吵死人女孩  你是第二号吵死人女孩
You be noisy girl number one. You be noisy girl number two.
很难相信  我们一直以为他很讨厌我们
I can't believe that this whole time we thought he hated us.
真是令人诧异  能如此触及别人的生命…
Isn't it amazing how much you can touch someone's life...
却浑然不觉
...without even knowing it?
你们看看这堆垃圾
Would you look at this dump?
他真的很恨我们  这是他最后的复仇
He hated us! This was his final revenge!
我从没见过这么多垃圾
Ever seen so much crap!
我想事实上  这间公寓污辱了垃圾的美名
Actually, I think this apartment sullies the good name of crap.
你们看看
Check this out.
这个可以给我吗
Can I have this?
你怎么可能不相信进化论
How can you not believe in evolution?
我不知道  就是不信  你们看看这件怪衬衫
I don't know, just don't. Look at this funky shirt!
菲比  我整个成年生涯都在研究进化论
Pheebs, I've studied evolution my entire adult life.
我们从全球各地搜集许多化石
And I can tell you, we've collected fossils from all over the world...
这些化石真的可以显现不同物种的进化
...that actually show the evolution of different species.
我是说  你真的可以看到
I mean, you can literally see them...
这些物种长时间的进化
...evolving through time.
真的  真的看得到
Really? You can actually see it?
那是一定的  美国 中国 非洲 全世界都有
You bet! In the U.S., China, Africa, all over!
这样啊  我不晓得
See, I didn't know that.
嗯  你长知识了
Well, there you go.
呵
Huh.
真正的关键在于是谁把化石放在那里的  又为了什么
So now the real question is, who put those fossils there and why?
看看这东西 〝我的牢骚语录〞
Hey. Look at this. My Big Book of Grievances.
嘿  有我
Hey, there's me.
〝4月17日  巨大的噪音…
"April 17th, excessive noise...
意大利佬带约会对象回家〞
...ltalian guy comes home with a date." Yeah.
钱德你看  也有你
Chandler, you're in here too.
〝4月18日  巨大噪音…
"April 18th, excessive noise...
意大利佬的同志室友带干洗衣物回家〞
...ltalian guy's gay roommate brings home dry cleaning."
嗯  记录得很好
Well, that's excellent.
摩妮卡  看看这盏灯
Monica, look at this lamp.
这算俗气或什么  这个我们一定要
Is this tacky or what? We have to have this.
我想我们一般的灯已经够多了
I think we have enough regular lamps.
什么  得了 我又不是…
What? Come on, it's not like...
想要这种娃娃型的钟  或什么的
...I'm asking for this girlie clock or anything.
对了  我觉得这个也很酷
Which, by the way, I also think is really cool.
喂  这跟我的东西不搭啦
Look, it doesn't go with any of my stuff.
嗯  那我的东西呢
Well, what about my stuff?
你又没有任何东西
You don't have any stuff.
你还是认为那是你的公寓对吧
You still think of it as your apartment, don't you?
不是  是  你是的
Mmm... No. Yes, you do.
你认为那是你的公寓  我只是租一间房间而已
You think of it as your apartment and I just rent a room.
唔
Mmm...
你继续〝嗯〞好了  我要去找个地方放我的新台灯
Okay, while you "mmm" on that, I'll go find a place for my new lamp.
好  菲比  看到我怎么动这些小玩具的吗
Okay, Pheebs. See how I'm making these little toys move?
拇指相对论
Opposable thumbs!
若非进化论  你如何解释拇指相对论
Without evolution, how do you explain opposable thumbs?
也许是那些太空舰长为了操纵太空舰才衍生的
Maybe the Overlords needed them to steer their spacecrafts.
跟我说你只是在开玩笑
Tell me you're joking.
喂  这样说好了  你相信某事但我不信
Look, can't we just say that you believe in something and I don't?
不  菲比  不可以   有何不可
No. No, Pheebs, we can't. Why not?
干嘛非要别人认同你的看法呢
What is this obsessive need you have to make everybody agree with you?
到底是为什么 你知道我所想
No, what's that all about? You know what I think?
也许是你把〝罗斯〞放在显微镜下的时候了
I think maybe it's time you put Ross under the microscope.
有血从我耳里喷出来吗
Is there blood coming out of my ears?
你们看  黑考斯的中学纪念册
Check it out. Heckles' high-school yearbook.
哇  他看起来很正常耶
Wow. He looks so normal.
他甚至有点可爱
He's even kind of cute.
〝黑考斯  连自然课你都能让我开怀大笑
"Heckles, you crack me up in science class.
你是全校最好玩的小孩〞
You're the funniest kid in school."
最好玩  黑考斯   上面是这样说的
Funniest? Heckles?  That's what it says.
黑考斯曾当选班上的小丑  我也是
Wow. Heckles was voted class clown, and so was I.
他是对的  你们听听看
He was right. Would you listen to that?
我也会称之为巨大的噪音
I'd call that excessive.
什么
Whoa. What?
黑考斯在乐团吹竖笛  我也吹竖笛
Heckles played clarinet in band, and I played clarinet.
他是模型社团的会员  我也是…
And he was in the scale modeler's club and I was...
我们是没有社团  不过我真的觉得他们很酷
Well, there was no club, but I sure thought they were cool.
那又怎样  你们两个都是书呆子
So? You were both dorks.
有啥大不了的
Big deal.
我只是觉得很诡异  知道吗  黑考斯跟我…
I just think it's weird, you know? Heckles and me...
黑考斯跟我  我…
Heckles and me. Me...
我跟黑考斯
Me and Heckles.
嘿  你们别吵了
Hey, would you knock it off!
啊
Ah!
你整晚都在这里吗
Have you been here all night?
看看这个
Look at this.
所有跟黑考斯交往过的女人
Pictures of all the women Heckles went out with.
看看他写的评语 〝薇薇安  太高〞
Look what he wrote on them. "Vivian, too tall."
〝玛斯  牙龈太露〞
"Madge, big gums."
〝太吵〞
"Too loud."
〝太聪明〞 〝吃东西时太大声〞
"Too smart." "Makes noise when she eats."
这就是我
This is me.
这就是我的作法
This is what I do.
我会一人孤独的死去  就像他这样
I'm gonna end up alone, just like he did.
钱德  黑考斯是个神经病
Chandler, Heckles was a nut case.
我们的火车走在相同的轨道上
Our trains are on the same track.
我是落后他30年  可是终点站完全一样
I'm coming up 30 years behind him, but the stops are all the same.
苦涩的小镇…
Bitter Town...
孤单的小城  隐者小站
...Alone-ville, Hermit Junction!
知道我们该怎么做吗  带你离开这里
You know what we gotta do? Get you out of here.
来吧  我请你吃早餐
Come on, I'll buy you breakfast.
万一我永远找不到对象呢  或更惨 万一我找到了…
What if I never find somebody? Or worse, what if I found her...
就因为她的口头禅是〝有可能〞就甩掉她了呢
...but I dumped her because she pronounces it "supposably"?
钱德  得了吧  你会找到对象的
Chandler, come on, you're gonna find somebody.
你哪会知道呢  哪会
How do you know that? How?
我是不知道  我只是想拉你一把
I don't know. I'm just trying to help you out.
你们都会结婚
You guys will all get married...
而我会孤寂而终
...and I'll end up alone.
你能答应我一件事吗
Will you promise me something?
等你结婚后  你可以都邀我过去过节吗
When you're married, will you invite me over for holidays?
我不晓得到时候  我们会想做什么
I don't know what we'll be doing.
我是指  万一我们得去她爸妈家过节呢
I mean, what if we're over at her folks' place?
对  我了解
Yeah, I understand.
你倒是可以过来看超级杯
You can come over and watch the Super Bowl.
每年都来  好吗
Every year, all right?
知道吗  我不要这种结局
You know what? I'm not gonna end up like this.
我们待会儿见  老兄
I'll see you, man.
咦呀
Jeez.
〝有可能〞
"Supposably."
有可能
Supposably.
他们到动物园去了吗
Did they go to the zoo?
有可能
Supposably.
嗨  是我
Hi. It's me.
哦  我的天
Oh, my God!
珍妮丝  你打给珍妮丝
Janice? You called Janice?
对  珍妮丝
Yes. Janice.
你们为何如此难以理解
Why is that difficult to comprehend?
你还记得珍妮丝吧
You remember Janice, right?
对  她很聪明  很漂亮  而且她真的很在乎我
Yes. She was smart, she was pretty and she honestly cared about me.
珍妮丝是我的最后机会
Janice is my last chance to have somebody.
哈罗
Hello.
哦  我的天
Oh, my God!
天啊  看看她变得多胖
Jeez, look how fat she got.
嘿  大家都在   嗨  珍妮丝
Hey, it's everybody. Hi, Janice.
珍妮丝  你已经…
Janice, you're...
对  我是
Yes, I am.
那是…   是你的吗
Is it...?  Is it yours? Ha!
少作梦了  钱德宾
You wish, Chandler Bing.
我现在可是一个已婚妇人了
You are looking at a married lady now.
噢
Oh.
耶
Yeah.
恭喜
Congratulations.
亲爱的  我很抱歉
Aw, sweetie, I'm sorry.
通电话时  你就不能先告诉我
You couldn't tell me on the phone?
然后呢  错失你惊讶的表情   哦  不行
And what? Miss the expression on your face? Oh, no.
珍妮丝也想开心一下
Janice likes to have her fun.
瑞秋  知道我们有一阵子没玩什么游戏了吗
You know what we haven't played in a while?
什么  〝把灯藏起来〞
What?  Hide the lamp.
摩妮卡  少来了
Monica, let it go.
你知道我对贝壳类过敏吗
Did you know I'm allergic to shellfish?
那你只好去吃别的台灯
Then you'll just have to eat the other lamps.
是那个可怕的科学人
Uh-oh. It's scary scientist man.
好  菲比  时候到了
Okay, Phoebe, this is it.
在这皮箱中 我带来真正的科学事实
In this briefcase I carry actual scientific facts.
请注意  是有一整箱的事实
A briefcase of facts, if you will.
这里有些化石 都是超过两亿年之久的
Some of these fossils are over 200 million years old.
在你开始前  我先声明  我不是在否认进化论
Okay, look, before you even start, I'm not denying evolution.
我是说那只是一种可能性
It's just one of the possibilities.
菲比  是唯一的可能性
It's the only possibility.
罗斯  请放开你的思想  就一点点行吗
Ross, could you just open your mind, like, this much? Okay?
过去也有最聪明的人  相信地球是扁的  不是吗
Wasn't there a time when the brightest minds in the world believe the Earth was flat?
50年之前  你们还认为原子是最小的东西…
And up till 50 years ago, you all thought the atom was the smallest thing...
直到你们打开了原子  才跑出一大堆鬼东西
...until you split it open and this whole mess of crap came out.
你现在却告诉我  你是如此难以置信的自大
Now, are you telling me that you are so unbelievably arrogant...
你完全不肯承认此事  的确有一点点  一丝丝
...that you can't admit that there's a teeny, tiny possibility...
错误的可能性
...that you could be wrong about this?
是有那么…
There might be...
一点点…
...a teeny...
一丝丝的…
...tiny...
可能性
...possibility.
真不敢相信你屈服了
I can't believe you caved.
什么   你刚抛弃你整个信仰系统
What? You just abandoned your whole belief system!
之前  我虽然不认同你  最起码我还敬重你
Before, I didn't agree with you, but at least I respected you.
可是…
But...
你明天要如何去上班
How are you gonna go into work tomorrow?
你将如何面对其他的科学人
How are you going to face the other science guys?
你将如何面对你自己
How are you going to face yourself? Oh...
真好玩  有谁饿了  我
That was fun. So who's hungry? I am.
我也是  我去拿我的外套
Me too. Let me just get my coat.
出什么事了   好吧   没事
What happened? Okay. All right.
是意外  我发誓
It was an accident, I swear.
我在穿外套然后那东东  那台灯  就破了
I was putting on my jacket and the thing and the lamp and it broke.
哦  拜托  摩妮卡  你一向讨厌我的灯
Oh, please, Monica! You've always hated my lamp!
如今  突然的神来一笔  它就破了
And now all of a sudden, it's just magically, it's just broken?
菲比  你告诉她
Phoebe, tell her?
好  我没看到  当时我也在穿外套
I didn't see it, because I was putting on my jacket.
不过  我想相信你
But I want to believe you.
钱德  摩妮卡刚刚打破我的贝壳灯
Hey, Chandler. Monica just broke my seashell lamp.
了不起
Neat.
我会孤寂而终
I'm gonna die alone!
好  算你赢
Okay, you win.
钱德  你不会孤寂而终的啦
Chandler, you are not gonna die alone.
珍妮丝本来是我的救生网  好吗
Janice was my safety net, okay?
现在我只好去找一条蛇了
And now I have to get a snake.
这又是为了什么
Uh-huh. Why is that?
如果我势必会成为孤伶伶的老头子  我就需要有个东西
If I'm gonna be an old, lonely man, I'm gonna need a thing.
像是依靠
You know, a hook.
就像在地下铁吃自己脸的那个家伙
Like that guy on the subway who eats his own face.
所以我想要成为〝带着蛇的疯子〞
So I figure I'll be "Crazy Man With A Snake."
疯狂的蛇人
Crazy Snake Man.
然后我会弄更多的蛇  叫他们我的宝贝
Then I'll get more snakes, call them my babies.
小鬼经过我住的地方都会用跑的
Kids won't walk past my place, they will run!
他们会边跑边叫〝逃离疯狂的蛇人〞
"Run away from Crazy Snake Man," they'll shout!
你得走出来才行
You've got to get over this. Okay?
你不会孤寂而终的
You won't end up alone.
我当然会
Of course I am.
我拒绝每一个疯狂到真的跟我交往的对象
I reject anyone who's crazy enough to actually go out with me...
然后我才来抱怨  这世上根本没有好女人
...and then I bitch that there aren't any great women out there.
钱德
Chandler
你刚刚的形容
You have just described...
其实就跟我们交往过的每一个男人一样
...virtually every man that we've ever gone out with.
耶
Yeah.
你不是怪物  你是一个正常男人
You are not a freak. You're a guy.
她是对的  你们全都一样
She's right. You're no different than the rest.
等等  等等  不  他不一样
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Yes, he is.
你完全不同   负面的不同
You are totally different. In a bad way?
不  亲爱的  是正面的
No, honey, in a wonderful way.
现在你知道自己要什么了
You know what you want now.
大部分的人根本浑然不觉
Most guys don't even have a clue.
你已经愿意冒险  愿意跟某人拥有亲密又不设防的关系
You're ready to take risks, be vulnerable and intimate with someone.
你不会孤寂而终的
You're not gonna end up alone.
钱德  你打给珍妮丝就代表你很想跟某人在一起！
You called Janice. That's how much you wanted to be with someone!
你成功了  你办到了
You've made it.  You're there.
你已经可以许下承诺了
You are ready to make a commitment!
这我还不能确定
Whoa! Don't know about that.
你拿的是什么东西
Wow. What you got there?
又是个不是你的  但可以被你打破的东西
Something else that's not yours that you can break?
不是
No.
我知道你喜欢这个  我要你收下
I know you like this and I want you to have it.
这东西放在我们公寓里会很搭
It'll look good in our apartment.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没问题
That's fine.
嘿   嘿
Hey. Hey.
知道了你们一定会很开心  明晚我有个约会
You'll all be pleased to know that I have a date tomorrow night.
这个女的叫艾莉森  是同事  她很棒
This woman Allison from work. She is great.
她很漂亮  很聪明  过去呢…
She's pretty, she's smart. And I've been...
我一直没邀她出来  是因为她有个…
...holding off asking her out in the past, because she has a...
不寻常的大头
...unusually large head.
不过  我不想再让这种事情耽误了
But I'm not going to let that stuff hang me up anymore. All right.
看看我  我长大了
Look at me. I'm growing.
纪念册是不能回收的吧
Hey, you can't recycle yearbooks, can you?
这个给我
I'll take that.
你要他的纪念册    对啊
You want his yearbook?  Yeah. Yeah.
有些人提到他的好  有人应该要收着这本的
Some people said nice things about him. Somebody should have it.
天哪  这真的很诡异
Gosh, this is so weird.
他的一生都在这间公寓里  现在一切都消失了
His whole life was in this apartment and now it's gone.
我们如果能纪念黑考斯几分钟  一定很好
I think it would be nice if we just took a few moments for Mr. Heckles.
他是有点烦人 是的 不过他 也是一个人
I mean, he was kind of a pain. He was, but he was a person.
什么
What?
你们全都下地狱去
You're all going to hell.
其实没那么大啦
It's really not that big.
你要带走  嗯   哦  对
Taking that with you, huh?  Oh, yeah.
嘿  你要走了吗
Hey, you coming?
再一下下
Yeah, in a second.
再见了  黑考斯先生
Goodbye, Mr. Heckles.
我们会尽量小声点
We'll try to keep it down.
我主修的科目很没用
ALLISON: My major was useless.
你看分类广告时  有常看到〝诚征哲学家〞吗
How often do you look in the classifieds and see "Philosopher Wanted"?
当然
Heh, heh. Sure.
我的天哪  好大一个头
My God, that's a big head!
在办公室时感觉没这么大  也许是灯光的缘故
It didn't look this big in the office. Maybe it's the lighting.
上班时  我的头看起来一定像颗高尔夫球而已
My head must look like a golf ball at work.
别执着于此事  快点  列出五点你喜欢她的地方
Don't get hung up on it. Quick, quick. List five things you like about her.
笑容可掬  穿着有品
Nice smile, good dresser.
大头  大头  大头
Big head, big head, big head!